- Alright, I'm about to go for my first ever ride in a fully autonomous vehicle.
我现在要第一次坐上全自动驾驶的汽车
Whoa, no driver.
哇，没有司机
All right.
好
Good morning, Derek.
早啊  Derek
This car is all yours with no one up front.
本车由您独享  前排没有司机
- I really like the idea of fully autonomous vehicles,
我挺喜欢全自动驾驶汽车这个概念的
but it's weird getting into a car with no driver
但真正坐上没司机的汽车  任其驾驶  感觉还是怪怪的
and just trusting the car.
I'm gonna report back how this ride goes
待会我会分享一下  这一趟下来跑得怎样
and how I feel about it.
以及我的一些感受
Oh, but full disclosure, this video is sponsored by Waymo.
但是先说清楚  本视频由Waymo赞助
Start ride.
行程开始
Ha ha!
哈哈
Make sure your seatbelt is fastened.
请系好您的安全带
For any questions, press the Help button to speak with a rider support agent.
如有任何问题  请按下帮助按钮来与客服通话
- Okay.
好
Now let's see where we go.
现在看看我们往哪走
It's looking at this car coming here. What's it gonna do?
那边来了一辆车 它会怎么应对呢
Oh, and it pulls in very smoothly behind it.
哦  很丝滑地跟在它后面
No problems. Did not turn into traffic.
没问题  没堵塞交通
Waited until the car has went, and then it turned.
等到前面车走了才转弯
I like that.
我喜欢
I polled YouTube viewers about autonomous vehicles
我在油管上开了一个自动驾驶汽车的投票
and half of you are excited and ready for them to be on the roads,
半数投票者很乐于尝试  认为这些车已经能上路了
but over 40% said you thought the technology was still over 10 years away.
但逾四成人认为  真正的自动驾驶至少还得等10年
And for those people, I have news,
对这些悲观者  我可要告诉你
which is that, well, there is no driver in this car.
我现在坐的车已经没有司机了
I'm currently inside a fully autonomous vehicle
我正在乘坐一辆全自动驾驶的汽车
driving around a suburb of Phoenix, Arizona.
驰骋在亚利桑那州的凤凰城市郊
Now I get that in some parts of the world,
我知道世界上还有一些
like, the roads aren't well enough maintained
道路维护不足  司机也比较野的城市
and people don't stay in their lane necessarily,
and so it'd be very hard for a computer to drive there,
这种情况  驾驶电脑可能还应付不来
but at least under good conditions, the technology is currently functional.
但至少在较好的路况下  自动驾驶已经能用了
- Now Waymo started out as the Google self-driving car project
Waymo一开始是谷歌的自动驾驶项目
with what is possibly one of the cutest cars ever made.
用着可能是世界上最最可爱的车
I am inside the world's first fully autonomous vehicle.
我现在坐在世界上第一辆全自动驾驶汽车里面
Back in October 2015, this car went on a public road,
2015年10月  这辆车上了公开道路
ridden by Steve Mann, who has a disability, he is legally blind,
乘客 Steve Mann 是一位盲人
but he could get around in this thing,
但他可以坐着这车到处转了
which is affectionately known as the Firefly.
这辆车被人们亲切地称为「萤火虫」
This is such a simple vehicle. There's basically nothing in here.
这车真的超级精简  里面差不多啥都没有
There's no steering wheel, no dashboard.
没有方向盘  没有仪表盘
This car is super basic.
这车太精简了
There is no AC,
连空调都没有
but there is an emergency stop button.
却有个紧急按钮
That's my favorite button in the car.
这车上我最喜欢这个按钮
It reminds me of elevators.
这使我联想到了电梯
You know, one of the important measures
你想 自动电梯里必定有的一样东西
that they had to put in automatic elevators
was a big red stop button.
就是那个大大红红的停止按钮
Did you know that before the 1940s, almost all elevators had drivers in them?
但你是否知道  在1940年以前  几乎每辆电梯都有司机
And when people started putting in driverless elevators,
后来当不用司机的电梯普及起来的时候
well, the public was very concerned,
公众十分担心  他们不想坐这种电梯
and they didn't wanna ride in those elevators.
There was one guy who was like,
甚至还有个人说
"I don't care if I have to walk up 12 flights of stairs for the rest of my life.
「我宁可后半辈子都走十二层楼梯
I'm not taking that elevator."
也坚决不坐自动电梯」
真香
And adoption was slow.
大众久久不能接纳
I mean, they tried to advertise to help people understand that it was in fact safe,
制造商想尽办法让公众相信  自动电梯很安全
but, ultimately, there was an elevator drivers strike in New York City,
但最后  是纽约电梯司机的罢工彻底激怒了大众
and that really annoyed people,
从而促使人们接受自动电梯
and it helped the adoption of automated elevators.
If you found a driver in an elevator today,
你今天如果看到电梯里有个操纵员
you would wonder, "Why are they there?"
你肯定很迷惑 「这人是干啥的」
Now you might think an elevator is just so simple,
你可能会说 电梯多简单啊
I mean, it is effectively one dimensional motion,
它不就只有一维运动吗
but airplanes are also flown extensively by computers.
但其实  飞机的大部分飞行工作也是计算机承担的
I saw this particular landing where a plane is coming in into Vienna,
我见过一次  一架飞机来到了维也纳
and it's just so foggy that the pilots can see almost nothing.
雾很浓  飞行员能见度很低
I mean, this is the view from the cockpit,
这是驾驶舱看到的样子
and yet, they make a perfect, a textbook landing right on target.
但是他们完成了一次教科书级别的降落  正中跑道
So how do they do it?
所以他们是咋做到的
The answer is the pilots didn't do it.
答案是  飞行员根本没操作
It was a CAT III autoland procedure.
这是一个三类自动降落流程 （**REVIEW：抓个ACI的人来看看？**）
The plane just came in and landed itself essentially.
飞机到了地点后  自动进场降落
Now, of course, the pilots are important
诚然  飞行员也很重要
and they're monitoring all of the instruments and controls,
他们要观察各个仪表和控制装置
but it's actually the plane and its computer getting the plane to land appropriately.
但归根到底  是机上的计算机自己完成的完美降落
I was surprised to learn that
我没想到的是
humans are much more likely to take manual control and land on sunny days,
人们在晴朗的天气  更倾向于手动操作降落
like July 6th, 2013,
比如2013年7月6日
BV11s411R7rt / av3613944
【ACI字幕组】空中浩劫S15：韩亚航空214号班机
when Asiana Airlines flight 214 was on final approach to San Francisco.
韩亚航空214号班机准备在旧金山机场降落
Attempting to manually land the plane,
在手动降落的过程中  飞行员不小心把节流阀打到零了
the pilot accidentally left the throttle at zero,
and by the time they realized and tried to abort the landing,
当他们意识到操作错误想要取消降落时
it was too late.
已为时已晚
The plane crashed into the runway seawall and split in two.
飞机一头撞进跑道海堤 一分为二
Three people died in the aftermath of this accident.
三人在这场灾难中不幸丧生
I think the counterintuitive thing is that
我认为有个反直觉的事实是
we expect the humans to be better, particularly in tough situations,
我们认为  人类面对复杂情况时的表现相对会更好
but when it comes to airplanes,
但在开飞机时  你反倒指望它在天气差的时候能自己飞
if it's bad weather, you actually want the plane flying itself.
So the obvious next question is,
很显然  下一个问题就是
would you want the same thing for cars?
同样的事会发生在汽车上吗？
There are all these different levels of autonomy
汽车自动化被分为这些级别
and everything up to four requires a human driver
四级 (L4) 以下的水平  都需要驾驶员持续观察和操作
to be responsible and at the wheel at all times.
In the early days of the Google self-driving car project,
谷歌早期的自动驾驶汽车
they had a vehicle that was not yet level four,
并没有达到L4
so it still required a human driver.
因此需要驾驶员
They let Google employees borrow the cars,
谷歌的员工可以借这些车来开
but they still had to be in control of the wheel.
但是要手动操作
And the volunteers were informed that
志愿者们也被告知  他们开车时得对这辆车全权负责
they were responsible for the car at all times
and that they would be constantly recorded, like video recorded,
并且他们在车内时将会被持续录像
while they were in the car.
But still, within a short period of time,
但是没过多久
the engineers observed drivers rummaging around in their bags
这些工程师就注意到驾驶员在包里翻翻找找
or checking phones,
刷手机
putting on makeup,
化妆
or even sleeping in the driver's seat.
甚至坐在驾驶座上睡大觉zzz
All these drivers were trusting the technology too much,
这些司机对这个科技太过信任了
2020年6月1日
台湾嘉义  特斯拉Model 3事故
which makes almost fully autonomous vehicles
使得这些近乎全自动驾驶的汽车  可能会比普通的车要更危险
potentially more dangerous than regular cars,
I mean, if the driver is distracted or not prepared to take over.
我指的是驾驶员分心了、没准备应对突发问题的情况
So this is why Waymo decided that the only safe way to proceed is
这就是为什么Waymo认为  唯一安全的方式是
with a car that has at least level four autonomy.
上路的自动驾驶汽车必须得达到L4级别
This is the depot where the cars go when they're not on the road,
还没用上的汽车就停在这个仓库
and it's also where people monitor all the rides in progress.
这里也有工作人员在监控所有正在进行的行程
我的团队就坐这里
你差不多可以看到有3支团队
其中一支是我带的车队调度团队
我们每天都要分配驾驶任务  保障所有行程都能顺利完成
然后是乘客支持团队  负责接听乘客的呼叫
Thank you for calling the Waymo Rider Support.
Waymo司机支持团队感谢您的来电
This is Beulah, how can I help today?
我是比拉  请问您需要什么帮助
- I just completed my ride, but I don't wanna get out of the car.
我刚跑完这趟行程  但我还想再多坐会
I just wanna keep driving.
我想让它继续开
Is there a way that I can do that?
我能再设置行程吗
Right now, I don't see a trip started.
您目前暂时没有已开始的行程
Give me one moment here while I partner with my team, okay?
我需要跟团队一同处理  请稍后
前方高亮警告
- Okay.
好
Well, I just left all my stuff in the car.
我的所有物品全丢车上了
I hope it comes back.
希望这车能转回来
- I think there's a lot of, still, resistance in terms of trusting the vehicle.
我认为  要想信任自动驾驶  仍然有很多阻力
And they ask you like, "How does it feel to be in a car without the driver?"
人们会问你 「在没有司机的情况下  在车里的感觉如何」
I was the first person to do public roads, fully driverless ride at night.
在公开道路上  我是在夜间进行全自动驾驶的第一人
I always share the experience with them.
我一直和人们分享我的经历
It takes about two minutes for you to completely
只要两分钟  你就能完全忘记自己坐着一辆没有司机的汽车
forget that you are in a driverless vehicle.
If the system really provides that feeling that you're safe
如果系统能让你切实体会到安全感
and you see a couple of maneuvers,
你又看到车跑得很熟练
in less than two minutes, you're talking to whoever is next to you
那不出两分钟  你就会跟旁边人开始唠嗑
and not paying attention to what's happening anymore.
不再关注驾驶情况
- Whoa,
哇
it doesn't make the indicator sound,
这车转向时没有“滴滴”声
so I just don't know when it's going to turn,
所以我（听声音）没法知道它啥时候会转弯
but if I was watching the map, I would know.
但我看地图就知道了
I think we have this bias to believe that
我们常常会高估了自己处理特定任务的水平
we're better at certain tasks than we actually are,
like thinking that people are good at driving.
比如说  估计自己擅长开车
Surveys show 74% of people believe they are above average drivers.
调查显示  74%的人认为自己的驾驶水平高于平均值
Think about that.
可想而知
In the 20th century, 60 million people were killed on the road.
在20世纪  有六千万人死于交通事故
That's basically an extra world war's worth of deaths.
死亡人数相当于又打了一场世界大战
And we really have no one to blame but ourselves.
但我们只能怪自己
The National Transportation and Safety Board has identified
国家运输安全委员会 (NTSB) 得出结论 *高亮警告
human error as the cause of 94% of accidents.
94%的交通事故是人为错误造成的
Most of these errors are impossible for a machine to make.
绝大多数这类错误是机器不可能犯的
Every year when people are backing out of driveways or parking spaces,
在美国  每年死于倒车事故的人多达200人
in the U.S, up to 200 people are killed,
and it's frequently older people or children, the children of the drivers.
死者多为老人和小孩  司机的小孩
It's awful.
太糟糕了
And it comes down to the fact that we don't have eyes in the back of our head,
这归根到底是因为  我们毕竟没在后脑勺长眼睛
and even the backup cameras still have blind spots.
即使是倒车雷达  也免不了存在盲区
But if you have a vehicle that has lidar, and radar, and 29 cameras,
但如果你的车子上有激光雷达、微波雷达  还有29个摄像头
you're just not going to hit them.
那就不会再碰上后面的人了
Up here in the very prominent top, there is a 360 lidar.
在车顶上有个硕大的360°激光雷达
So it can see all around the car.
它对周遭事物能一览无余
It can see up to 300 meters away with a lidar.
激光雷达能识别到300米外的东西
The way the lidar works is it shoots out invisible laser beams,
激光雷达的工作原理是  发射肉眼不可见的激光束
scanning around millions of times a second,
每秒扫描周围百万次
and then it detects the reflection,
它会探测反射的激光
and how long it takes to come back
计算激光来回的时间  即可知道外部事物距车有多远
allows you to determine how far it is to that object.
So what it's doing is like painting a 3D picture of the world.
它所做的就好比是给环境画了张三维的画
There are 29 cameras around this vehicle,
车子全身有29个摄像头
which gives you full 360 vision.
提供了360°全方位的视野
It gives you close range vision, what is right next to the car,
它能看得近  近到紧挨着车子的东西
and also long range vision, going out 500 meters.
也能看到远到500米外的东西
This car could detect a stop sign or a pedestrian 500 meters away.
它能识别出500米外的停车路牌和行人
How many of us have eyesight that is that good?
没几个地球人有这么好的视力
There is also a microphone up on top
顶上还有个麦克风
to listen to what's happening in the environment,
来倾听周围环境发生了什么
and if there are sirens, then the car will pull over to the side of the road.
如果有警笛声  车子会靠边停
It's gotta be able to respond to emergency vehicles.
它能够对应急车种有所反应
What I wanna see here is, how does it handle a parking lot
我想看看它如何应对停车场的环境
where there's people driving in unusual ways and
停车场里的开车方式不同于道路
possibly pedestrians walking around?
并且会有行人到处走
Whoa.
哇
That was a sudden stop.
来了个急停
The car made a pretty hard stop there.
这刹车怕是踩死了
I think it saw that guy with a cart coming up on a pedestrian crosswalk.
它应该看到了那个推车的人走到了人行横道上
And one of the interesting things that the vehicle is always doing is
这辆车一直在用一种有趣的驾驶方式
not only seeing where things are and where they're going,
它不单单看到事物在哪里，在往哪边移动
but also making predictions about where they're likely to go.
它还会预测事物最有可能往哪边移动
So this car doesn't just have one potential future.
所以这车并非一定会刹停  也可能有其他反应
It's constantly imagining, "Well, he might cross at the crosswalk,"
它不断地想象 「嗯  他可能会在人行横道上过马路」
or, "He might keep going," or, "He might turn left,"
或者「他可能会继续走」或者「他可能会左转」
and so it has to be prepared for all of those different options.
它得对这多种可能统统做好准备
And it even weights the options
它还会衡量各种选项的可能性
of like how likely it thinks that he's gonna go on the crosswalk
比如说  这人有多大可能上人行横道
versus go straight versus turn.
又有多大可能直走或者左转
And you can see that with the thickness of the line
这在他们的模拟图像中以线条粗细的方式来体现
in the little simulated graphic that they have.
A few years back, I think a lot of people were talking about
几年前有很多人在讨论
how autonomous vehicles have to figure out who to hit in case of an accident,
发生事故时  自动驾驶汽车要如何抉择该撞谁
like do the pick the orphan or the nun?
要撞孤儿还是修女（**REVIEW：不知道是不是俗语**）
无人驾驶汽车混乱的伦理
Should the car hit the motorcyclist with the helmet on
这车是应该撞右边带了头盔的摩托车手…
because his injuries might be less severe
因为他受的伤不会那么重呢
or should the car hit the motorcyclist who does not have a helmet on
还是应该撞左边没带头盔的摩托车手…
because he did not properly protect himself?
因为他没有好好保护自己？
If cars were programmed to hit the motorcyclist with the helmet,
如果这车的程序被设定为  去撞戴了安全帽的车手
that would mean that, in a way, it would become safer to ride without a helmet.
那从某种意义上来说  不带安全帽的车手反而更安全了
But the reality is that 99% of accidents aren't like that.
可在现实中  99%的事故都不是这样的啊
Every year, around 1.3 million people are killed on the roads,
每一年  大约有130万人死于交通事故
almost all of them due to human error.
绝大部分都是人为失误导致
If autonomous cars can reduce these fatalities,
如果自动驾驶汽车能够减少事故死亡
then the real moral dilemma is not getting them on the road sooner
那么真正导致这些车没法上路的道德困境在于
for fear we haven't worked out exactly how they'll react
因为我们惧怕车在极小概率情况下的反应尚未清楚
to extremely unlikely hypothetical scenarios.
I think humans are becoming worse drivers
人类正在成为更差的司机
because we're just so prone to distraction.
因为我们真的太容易分心了
Think about the main reasons why cars crash:
想想撞车的主要原因
because people are speeding, they're under the influence, they're distracted.
就是人们超速了、受到什么影响了、分心了
I mean, these sorts of problems, an autonomous vehicle would not have.
我认为这些问题都是自动驾驶汽车不会有的
You don't get a distracted driver.
电脑“司机”永远不会分心
The ultimate question, right,
这个终极问题的答案  也是我和所有人都想知道的
that everyone wants to know, that I want to know the answer to is,
as these vehicles stand, are they better than the average human?
就目前的自动驾驶水平而言  它们是否优于人类的平均水平
Not than the best human, but just like an average human.
不和最好的比  但能不能达到普通人的水平
Like replacing some random car on the street with one of these vehicles,
比如说随机把大街上的一些车换成自动驾驶汽车
does that make the road safer?
会让这条路更安全吗？
- Yes, it does.
答案是肯定的
I think we would never launch a rider-only service
我想  如果一个没有司机的乘车服务不满足基础的安全框架
if we did not meet that base safety framework.
那我们坚决不会向大众推行这项服务
- If that's true, it means like
如果这是真的，这就意味着
every vehicle that's not on the road is kind of a worse situation,
所有不在路上的车都处于更糟糕的情况
do you know what I mean?
懂我意思吗
- We are really working really hard to launch this
我们真的在想尽办法  往更广阔的领域提供自动驾驶服务
in larger areas and new areas too,
but we need to have the experience
但我们需要更多的实践经验
to show the regulators why we believe it's safer,
来向监管机构证明「我们相信它更安全」
and, for that, you need to be driving miles,
为此需要更多的行驶里程
a number of miles that you feel comfortable with, statistically speaking.
从统计学角度来说要多到让人足够放心
- These vehicles have way more experience than any human driver
这些车的驾驶经验比任何一位人类老司机都多
because they've now accumulated data
因为他们在公共道路上收集的行驶数据  已超过两千万英里
over 20 million miles of driving on public roads.
If you were an average driver, you'd have to drive for a thousand years
普通司机需要开上一千年的车  才能积累这么多里程
to accumulate that sort of experience.
And all of that experience can be used to train the systems, to fix the software,
Waymo积累的所有经验都可用于训练系统、修正软件
and used across all the vehicles in the fleet.
然后广泛应用于所有现行车辆
In 2019, Waymo released a study of its data,
在2019年  Waymo发布了一份数据研究报告
over 6.1 million miles of automated driving
基于超过610万英里的  在凤凰城都市圈的自动驾驶路试
in the Phoenix, Arizona metropolitan area.
Of the 18 total accidents that occurred during the study,
这次研究总计发生了18起事故  在这些事故中
none were serious enough to expect significant injury or death.
没有一项是严重到会导致重大伤亡的
In Waymo's Safety Report,
在Waymo的安全报告中
they found some types of accidents have been
他们发现  自动驾驶系统已让某些类型的事故不复存在
completely eliminated by this autonomous driving system,
like the car doesn't go off the road
车子不会驶离道路
and it doesn't hit stationary objects.
也不会撞击静止物体
Humans, humans do those things.
人类才会犯这种错
If you look at the eight significant accidents that happened with Waymo vehicles
至于他们这600万英里的行驶中  发生的八起重大安全事故
over the six million miles of driving,
all eight of them involve a human driver
这些事故都涉及到  另一辆车有个不守交规的人类司机
of another vehicle doing something stupid,
like driving on the wrong side of the road
比如  逆行
or running a red light
闯红灯
or going through a stop sign
看到停止路牌却不停车
or failing to yield
让路失败
or going 20 miles per hour over the speed limit.
超速  比上限高了每小时20英里
There were three incidents involving Waymo vehicles and pedestrians,
有三起事故的当事双方是Waymo的车辆和行人
but in all three, the Waymo vehicle was stationary
但在这三起事故中  Waymo的车都是静止的
and the pedestrian or cyclist/skateboarder ran into the vehicle.
是行人、自行车手、滑板者撞向车辆
Waymo also takes some of that real-world data
Waymo也采集了一些真实世界数据
and they put it into simulations
放进了模拟系统中
and they tweak it a bit.
并稍微调整了一下
So they try adding like a bicyclist going fast or going slow,
他们试着加入一个骑得很快或者很慢的自行车手
or they make the car turn faster or slower.
或者让车加速或减速
So they change all these parameters and variables,
他们更改这些参数与变量
and they see what the software will do.
观察程序会如何应对
And they've trained the software on an additional 20 billion miles of driving,
他们额外投入了200亿英里的模拟里程去训练程序
not on the road but in the simulation,
so that's a thousand times more experience again.
所以这又多了成千倍的经验
The question for me is,
我的问题是
when is stepping inside an autonomous car
等到什么时候  坐上自动驾驶汽车的感觉
gonna feel the same as stepping inside an elevator?
才能无异于坐电梯的感觉？
Because I think that time may be coming sooner than you think.
因为我觉得  这个时刻会比你们想像的来得更快
I like the idea of this technology,
我喜欢这个技术点子
but, honestly, getting in the car, I wasn't quite sure how I would feel.
但说实话  刚坐上这车时  我不知道我会有个啥体验
I was a little bit uncertain,
我一开始还不太肯定
but once I saw.. it just handles so confidently...
但等我看到  它开起来如此驾轻就熟之后…
Like driving is one of those things that I feel like
开车这种东西嘛  水平是骡子是马一遛就知道了
you can't hide whether you're a good or bad driver.
It's just like, "Oh, what's gonna happen when
比如说  如果那里停着辆车、有个人骑单车或者步行会怎样
there's a parked car or a cyclist or a pedestrian,"
and it just sort of handles all those situations with such confidence and ease
这车能如此从容自信、驾轻就熟地处理所有这些情况
that I think I stopped thinking about it.
我觉得我不必再担心了
- After they pass a couple of your mental tests,
你在内心里给它打分通过之后
you're like, "I'm good. I think I can.. I'll be okay."
你会觉得「我可以  我觉得…  我应该没事」（笑
- Yeah, yeah, I felt the same way.
对  我也是这种感觉
I think a lot of people miss the bigger implications of what is achievable
许多人意识不到  等到全自动驾驶真正普及之时
once fully autonomous driving is commonplace.
究竟能产生多么深远的影响
Riders with disabilities, seniors, and the blind can get around more easily.
残疾人、老年人、盲人乘客出行会方便得多
Transportation will get cheaper.
运输会越来越便宜
Think of all the wasted value in the cars that spend over 95% of their time parked.
想想那些每天上路时间不超过5%的车  浪费了多少资源
We can regain a bunch of time and feel happier
我们可以重新利用这些时间变得更快乐
because commuting and being stuck in traffic sucks.
因为上下班还堵车糟透了
We can reduce traffic because vehicles will have better awareness of each other.
我们可以减少交通堵塞  因为车子会更了解彼此
You can imagine one day when all the cars are fully autonomous,
可以想象  有朝一日  路上的所有车都是全自动驾驶的时候
they can execute a beautiful ballet driving together,
往来车辆可以交织通行  像芭蕾舞一样优雅
and when that time comes, we can eliminate parking lots
等那一天真正到来之时  我们将再也不需要停车场
and add green spaces to our cities.
给城市节省出了更多的绿化空间
And, most importantly, widespread adoption of autonomous cars
最重要的是  全自动驾驶汽车的普及
could prevent tens of thousands of fatalities in the U.S. alone.
光是在美国  就能避免数以万计的交通事故
When do you think that this will be a reality,
你什么时候会觉得这会成为现实
like, clearly it's coming, but when?
显然这一切快来了  但具体是啥时候
- Yeah. If you're talking about big cities,
如果你说的是大城市
I'm hoping the next five years will be really game changing.
我希望接下来的五年的变化将会很大
- I'm excited to see it.
我很期待能亲眼看到
- Me too, believe me. Believe me. I just don't want to commute to work anymore.
我也一样  相信我  我真的不想再开车上班了
I would love to sit in the backseat,
我会爱上坐在后座  在来回的路上做我的工作
do my work on the way there and on the way back.
- Or do something fun, watch a movie.
或者做点什么有意思的  比如看看电影
- Or sleep, yeah.
或者睡觉（笑